Looking for a postdoctoral position in Computer Vision

Pierre Jacob

Paris area, France (+33) 6 62 41 64 80 pierre.jacob@ensea.fr linkedin.com/in/pierre-jacob github.com/pierre-jacob

ABOUT ME

I am a PhD student in Computer Vision and Deep Learning at CY Paris University. My research interests include computer vision and deep learning. Specifically, I work on high-order representations, dictionary learning and attention-based approaches in deep metric learning.

OBJECTIVES

I am looking for a postdoctoral research position to tackle metric learning oriented tasks using supervised or unsupervised learning. Especially, I would like to focus on dictionary learning, manifold-based approaches, sparse representation or high-order representations. I may also consider to work on few/one/zero-shot learning, domain adaptation, transfer learning but also certifiable or explainable Al for computer vision tasks.

LANGUAGES

French English Native speaker Proficient (TOEIC 830)

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND FRAMEWORKS

Python Tensorflow Keras Matlab Java - C# C



EDUCATION

Sept. 2020 -Mar. 2017 (Paris area, France)

PhD at CY Paris University

- Title: "High-order statistics for representation learning"
- Supervisors: David Picard, Aymeric Histace and Edouard Klein
- Fine-grained image analysis (bilinear pooling, higher-order pooling, dictionary learning)
- Deep metric learning (example generation with GANs, regularization methods, attention models)

Sept. 2016 -Sept. 2015 (Paris area, France)

MSc at Cergy-Pontoise University

- MSc in Computer Science with honors
- Major specialization in "Artificial Intelligence and Robotics"
- Minor in image processing

Sept. 2016 -Sept. 2013 (Paris area, France)

MSc at ENSEA School of Engineering

- A three-year program in a French engineering graduate school
- Graduated with high honors
- Fields of study: telecommunication electrical electronics – computer science engineering
- Specialization in "Electronics and Embedded Systems"

WORK HISTORY

Sept. 2016 -Apr. 2016 (Angers area, France)

Limagrain Group

R&D intern

- Automatic seed classification and disease detection using machine learning and multispectral imaging
- Gaussian mixture models, neural networks, linear discriminant analysis
- Real-time implementation using Matlab and C# (more than 5 seeds per second)

Aug. 2015 -July 2015 (Paris area, France)

Cergy-Pontoise University

Research engineer intern

- 3D-printed hand design and control for bioinspired robotic
- 3D design modification and hardware + software development

INTERESTS

Personal projects

- Keras backend for deep learning inference for System-on-Chip with FPGA accelerator
- Supervision of student projects in computer vision (application to mimic the Terminator vision, airsoft helmet with AR, ...)

TEACHING

Sept. 2020 -Sept. 2018 (Paris area, France)

Part-time professor in Pattern Recognition at EISTI School of Engineering

- Responsible for teaching an introduction course concerning pattern recognition (28h per year)
- Machine learning algorithms (SVM, LDA, GMM, regression, among others), feature matching and aggregation (BoVW, VLAD), deep learning
- Python toolkits: scikit-learn/image, numpy tensorflow, keras

Sept. 2020 -Sept. 2017 (Paris area, France)

Part-time professor in Computer Science at ENSEA School of Engineering

- Practical work supervisor for a Kernel programming course: Shell and FTP development in C (16h per year)
- Responsible for teaching the course "Artificial Intelligence for Optimal Control" (16h per year)

MAIN PUBLICATIONS

- [1] **Pierre Jacob**, David Picard, Aymeric Histace and Edouard Klein. "Improving Deep Metric Learning with Virtual Classes and Examples Mining". In submission.
- [2] **Pierre Jacob**, David Picard, Aymeric Histace and Edouard Klein. "DIABLO: Dictionary-based Attention Block for Deep Metric Learning". In submission.
- [3] **Pierre Jacob**, David Picard, Aymeric Histace and Edouard Klein. "Metric Learning with HORDE: High-Order Regularizer for Deep Embeddings". In IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (**ICCV**), 2019.
- [4] **Pierre Jacob**, David Picard, Aymeric Histace and Edouard Klein. "Efficient Codebook and Factorization for Second Order Representation Learning". In IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), 2019.
- [5] Gaetan Raynaud, Camille Simon Chane, **Pierre Jacob**, Aymeric Histace. "Active Contour Segmentation based on Histograms and Dictionary Learning for Video-capsule Image Analysis". In International Joint Conference on Computer Vision, Imaging and Computer Graphics Theory and Applications, 2019.
- [6] Romain Leenhardt, Pauline Vasseur, ..., **Pierre Jacob**, Camille Simon Chane, Olivier Romain. "A neural network algorithm for detection of GI angiectasia during small-bowel capsule endoscopy". In Gastrointestinal endoscopy, 2019.
- [7] Marc Souchaud, **Pierre Jacob**, Camille Simon Chane, Aymeric Histace, Olivier Romain. "Mobile Phones Hematophagous Diptera Surveillance in the field using Deep Learning and Wing Interference Patterns". In IFIP/IEEE International Conference on Very Large-Scale Integration, 2018.
- [8] **Pierre Jacob**, David Picard, Aymeric Histace and Edouard Klein. "Leveraging Implicit Spatial Information in Global Features for Image Retrieval". In IEEE International Conference on Image Processing (**ICIP**), 2018.